<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="help_default">Default Help.</string>
    <string name="help_map">The Map displays one or more routes.
        When you tap on any point on the map,
        you are taken to a list of routes that have stops near the point that you tapped on.</string>
    <string name="help_nearby">The <b>Nearby</b> screen displays the nearest routes to your current location,
      or to a location that you previously selected by tapping on the map, or from a route stop.</string>
    <string name="help_stops">
A distance in parenthesis is a straight line distance from the current location or from a reference location.
A distance with a + or - sign is a <i>route distance</i>, the distance along the route
from a reference location on the route.  A positive distance means that the stop is ahead of you.
A negative distance means that the stop is behind you as you travel along the route.
\n\n
The reference route location is the current location, if you are on the route,
or the closest route location to your current location,
or the beginning of the route.    
</string>    
    <string name="help_stop">
If the application has detected that you are following the given route, it computes your average speed
and consequently the estimated time of arrival (ETA) to the chosen stop.
The computation uses the planned route distance (including turns) rather than the straight line distance.
\n
The average speed is computed from the earliest known time that you were following the route.
This is currently computed only within this screen.
To get a better estimate, stay on the screen for about a minute.
\n
The screen also computes the estimated time it would take you to walk to this stop, if you were walking
1.3 times the straight line distance to the stop at 5 Km/h.
Use this to check if it would be faster to walk than wait for the next bus.
\n
If you are waiting for the bus at this stop,
you can use the distance of the stop from the route start
to estimate how long it takes the bus to get here.
The application currently does not compute such an estimate, but
if you know the approximate speed of the bus from your own measurements,
(perhaps using this application, or any GPS tracking application)
you can compute a rough estimate yourself.
Assuming a speed of V Km/h, multiply the route Km distance by 60/V.
\n
For example, if you assume that the bus goes at an average speed of 20 Km/h,
multiply the distance in Km by 3 (60/20) to get the time in minutes.
\n
We would like to provide this computation in a future version
but we would need speed data.
</string>   

<string name="help_about">
<b>Athens Next Bus</b>, version %1$s
Written by Alex Athanasopoulos, Copyright &#169; 2012.\n\n
The route maps and timetables are provided by OASA and are available to the public from www.oasa.gr.
Contact OASA to fix errors in its timetables and contact me to fix bugs in the application.
\n
If you notice a mistake in a route timetable (e.g. the scheduled departure time shown by the application
does not match the time posted at the start bus stop):
\n
1. Check www.oasa.gr to see if the error is in their data.\n
2. If so, contact OASA directly (by phone or email) and ask them to correct it.\n
3. If this application does not match the OASA website,
please contact me so I can fix the bug or update the application with the latest information from OASA.
\n\n
I can be contacted at alex@melato.org        
</string>    
    
</resources>